- 好了嗎? -馬上來
You done? - Yes. Almost.
快點，快點
Hurry up. Hurry up.
今天我們早點到，坐前排
Today we'll reach early and take the front row.
我終於做完了DPP試卷
After so long I've completed the DPP.
巴特拉先生說得對
Batla sir is right.
無機物學的好，冇有問題解不了 -是的
If one knows inorganic the questions get solved instantly. - Yes.
天知道他們為什麼教原子軌道
Lord knows why they teach SPDF orbital.
就應該從無機物開始
They should begin with Inorganic.
這樣學生的自信心一定能夠得到提升 -是的
That ways student's confidence will get a boost. - Yes.
這是我第一次在15分鍾內做完DPP
For the first time I could finish the DPP in fifteen mins.
我十二分鍾就做完了
I finished in twelve.
有可能冇有仔細讀題
Well, it's possible you made some mistakes in haste.
- 走著瞧 - 真的嗎？
Wait for it to be discussed. - Really?
好吧，我們走著瞧
Well, alright. We shall see.
分數低的人
The one who has more correct answers..
要請對方吃泡芙
..has to treat the other to Shreeji's onion puffs.
那就來賭一把
It's a bet. - It's a bet.
-你會輸的 -快走吧
You will lose. - Come. Come. Come.
你應該加快速度了，這題用了你15分鍾
You have to do something. It took you 15 minutes.
花點時間冇問題，但要做得完美
One should take time but do it perfectly.
瓦伊巴夫潘迪！
Vaibhav Pandey!
是的，阿姨
Yes, aunty.
瓦伊巴夫潘迪-什麼事？
Vaibhav Pandey. - Yes, aunty.
你的風扇昨天冇關-不，阿姨，風扇關了
Your fan was left on yesterday. - No, aunty. The fan was off.
冇關! -也許是你冇關
It was on! - Maybe it was left on.
阿姨，風扇關了-不要說謊
Aunty, the fan was off. - Don't tell lies.
我能聽到風扇的聲音
I could hear the fan on full speed all the way up.
阿姨，在我們的房間聽不到風扇的聲音 -嗯
Aunty, when the sound of our fan can't be heard our room. - Yes.
在你的房間裏怎麼可能聽到聲音？
How can the sound of our fan be heard in your room?
別跟我說你那些物理學理論
Don't apply your physics in this matter..
如果你晚上再不關空調
..because if the fan is left on again..
我就用我的數學理論，給你下個月的房租漲200盧比
..I shall apply my math and increase 200 rupees in the rent next month.
邦蒂！
Bunty!
阿姨……
Aunty. List..
走，走，走
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
老巫婆! 她一邊刷牙還要一邊要錢
Old hag! She is demanding money whilst brushing her teeth.
那就把錢給她-這不是錢的問題
So give her the money. - It's not about the money.
拉裏塔 · 帕瓦爾！
Lalita Pawar!
在我爸麵前，她錶現得像妮露帕 · 羅伊
In dad's presence she was acting like Nirupa Roy.
"他就像我的兒子"
He is like my Bunty.
"我喜歡..." 該死！
I like.. Damn!
即使我不得不關著風扇睡覺
Even if I have to sleep with the fan off..
我也絕不會給她漲房租的借口
..I won't give her an excuse to increase the rent.
好吧，先別想這個了
Okay. You can think about Tarka later.
我們去前排搶個位置，讓他們看看
Let's sit in the first bench now and show them.
還剩10分鍾下課
Only ten minutes left in class.
大家註意了
Everybody pay attention.
這是一個非常重要的例外
This is a very important exception.
這是 JEE 2005年真題
It was asked in JEE 2005.
碘化銀是離子化合物，但它不溶於水
Silver Iodide is an ionic compound still it's not soluble in water.
為什麼? 因為這適用於法楊原則
Why? Because Fajan's rule applies here.
什麼是法楊原則?-冇有離子化合物是完全離子的
What was it? - No ionic compound is completely ionic..
冇有一種共價化合物是完全共價的
..and no covalent compound is completely covalent.
非常好！
Very good!
是的，米娜爾，你看
Right, Meenal. You see..
就這樣你的排名就上升了500
Just like that your rank just rose by 500
從印度理工的計算機科學轉嚮孟買冶金學
and you move from Computer Science in IIT BHU to Metallurgy IIT Bombay.
看到了吧，無機物可以幫你提高排名
Look, its Inorganic that improves rank.
你的排名是多少，先生？
What was your rank, sir?
什麼?DPP？
What? DPP.
好的，那讓我們來看 DPP
Yes, yes. Let's do DPP.
你們都拿出來，快點
All of you bring it out. Come on.
把這個修好
Get this repaired.
有一件很重要的事情 -是的，先生
This is most important. - Yes, sir.
請講
Please continue.
這是教師反饋錶
These are the faculty feedback forms.
兩天之內填好交上來
Fill if you care to and return them in two days.
另外距離第三期付款隻剩下五天了
And only five days remain towards the third installment.
下一堂課也將由巴特拉主講，先生
And the next lecture will also be given by Batla.... sir.
班薩爾先生已經去羅馬尼亞參加數學奧林匹克了
As you might be knowing Bansal sir has gone to Romania for the Math Olympiad.
- 國外?-是的
Abroad? - Yes.
還有你，去理個發
And you. Get a haircut.
你是哪個班的？
Where are you loitering?
好了，我們看一下DPP吧 -好的，先生！
Yes. So, let's do the DPP. - Yes, sir!
很好! 我喜歡興奮狀態
Good! I like excited state.
很好！
Good!
第一題答案是A
Yes. So, the first answer is A.
第二題C
The second answer is C.
第三題D
The third answer is D.
第四題答案是
The fourth answer is
B
B.
第六題答案是C
The sixth answer is C.
B
B.
C
C.
現在把你的分數寫在試卷上
Now write your marks on the DPP.
然後把它們保存好以後複習
And keep them away for revision.
15題是怎麼回事，先生
And what about the 15th, sir.
那是額外的獎勵題
That is a chocolate problem.
這題是給A1的學生出的，你可以不用看
I included that exclusively for the A1 batch. You skip it.
好的，先生 -等下，先生
Okay, sir. - Sir! Sir!
先生，第14個問題的答案怎麼可能是C？
Sir, how can the answer to the 14th question be C?
這不能變成化合物
Sir, this cannot become a compound.
不符合八隅體規則
The octet rule will break here.
是的，你完全正確
Yes. You are absolutely correct.
- 所以呢?-這是個例外，孩子
So? - This is an exception, son.
例外？
Exception?
但是，先生，科學不能打破規則
But, sir, rules cannot break in science.
誰告訴你的？
Who told you that?
例外是化學的規律
Exception is the rule of chemistry.
明白了嗎？
Got it?
來吧，我們開始分析鹽，坐下吧
Come on. Let's start salt analysis. Sit down. Sit down.
坐下
Sit down.
好了，註意了，大家都聽著
Okay, so. Pay attention. Everybody listen.
這很重要
It's very important.
你笑什麼? 你隻答對了三道題
Why are you laughing? You got three answers correct.
你才對兩個，請客吧
You got two. Puffs.
我們都答的很認真
We took this very lightly, bro.
我還以為這是小菜一碟，但其實不是 -是的，兄弟，這當然不是小菜一碟
Thought it's a piece of cake . It isn't. - Yes, bro. It's certainly not a piece of cake.
今天特別辣
It is extremely spicy today, bro.
水
Water.
兄弟，水
Brother. Water.
給，吃這個吧
Here. Have this.
拿著這個
Hold this.
放鬆放鬆
Easy. Easy.
好嗎？
Okay?
可以都給我嗎?-可以
May I have it all? - You may.
把包裝紙給我就好 -謝謝
Just give me the wrapper. - Thank you.
包裝紙？
Wrapper?
他一定是個環保主義者
He must be eco-friendly.
非常有前途
Very promising.
不，不，這不是普通的包裝紙，是我的獎杯
No, no. These are not wrappers. They are my trophies.
我解決的第四個獎勵題
My fourth chocolate problem.
你能解決獎勵題嗎？
You can solve the chocolate problem?
你在 A6，是嗎?-那又怎樣？
You are in A6, aren't you? - So?
不僅僅是我，還有其他五個同學也做到了
Not just me. Five others have also done it.
你說什麼? -冇錯，跳過這題，這是給A1學生出的
What are you saying? - Exactly, don't do it. It is only for the A1 batch.
把包裝紙給我
Give me the wrapper.
兄弟
Bro.
你多少……我不是很在意的哈
So, how much.. Not that it matters to me.
你在無機DPP考試中得了多少分？
How much do you score in Inorganic DPP?
無機物？
In inorganic?
12、13分吧
About 12 or 13.
你呢？
You?
13、14分那樣子
13 or 14 types.
是的，13、14分
Yes. 13 or 14.
非常有前途! 非常有前途！
Very promising! Very promising!
他們可以解決獎勵題
These people can solve the chocolate problem.
A6和我們A5有什麼不同？
What is different in their A6 from our A5?
牆壁的顔色，長凳的寬度
The color of the walls. The width of the benches.
粉絲的數量
The number of fans.
還有教職員工
Also, the faculty.
怎麼了？
Why?
來吧，我知道了
Come. I'll tell you.
來來來
Come. Come. Come.
你在幹什麼? 你瘋了嗎？
What are you doing? Are you insane?
給他零分，零分
Give him zero. Zero.
如果巴特拉的教學不合格
If Batla's teaching isn't up to the mark..
我們會給他什麼樣的反饋？
..what will we give him in the feedback form?
給他零分，對吧？
We will give him a zero, won't we?
判低分和羞辱學生是老師的事情，而不是學生
Awarding bad marks and humiliating thereafter suits teachers, not students.
這也是來自A5的
That too from A5.
你這個笨蛋! 如果我們不給出糟糕的反饋
You dork! If we don't give bad feedback..
他隻會繼續教下去
..he only will continue to teach.
那你怎麼學無機物呢？
Then how will you learn inorganic?
老師和家長是平等的
Teachers are equal to parents.
那麼你也應該給他們反饋
Then you should give them feedback too.
爸爸，你不是一個稱職的父親
Dad, you are not up to the mark as a father.
以後隔壁王叔叔睡在你的臥室裏
Hereafter uncle will sleep in your bedroom.
冇道理的，冷靜點
That doesn't make sense. Cool down.
去把風扇打開
Go and switch on the fan.
風扇今天不開了
The fan won't be switched on today.
但是我覺得有點熱
But I am feeling a little hot.
先填反饋錶，然後打開風扇
Fill the form first. Then the fan will be switched on.
我要去喝水
I am going to drink water.
米納！
Meena!
這是一個領先的時代
There was this 'Dwapar' era..
像德羅納查裏亞這樣的大師在過去備受尊敬
..when Gurus like Dronacharya used to be respected.
這就是這個時代……-嘿! 就連阿俊都和德羅納查裏亞打過仗
And here is this era.. - Hey! Even Arjun fought Dronacharya.
你連《羅摩衍那》都冇學好
Even your Ramayana is weak..
德羅納查裏亞先生是有史以來最好的老師
..where as Dronacharya sir was like the best teacher ever.
史上最好的老師！
Bestest teacher ever!
但他還是和他打了起來，為什麼？
And yet he fought with him. Why?
逮捕陰謀
For seizure of a plot.
而你甚至不能在反饋錶上給巴特拉老師打低分
And you, Meena, can't even fill a single feedback form against Batla for JEE.
如果是我，我會從這裏跳下去
If it were me, I'd have leapt from here.
你自己給他低分吧，我不幹
Go ahead. Give him bad marks. I won't do it.
好吧
Okay.
好吧，好吧
Okay. Fine. Fine.
你也會像巴特拉一樣，爛在一些私立工程學院裏
You'll also rot in some private engineering college like that Batla of yours.
考不上印度理工的渣渣
Bloody non-IITians.
嘿！
Hey!
怎麼了?-冇什麼，阿姨
What's going on? - Nothing, aunty.
水灑出來了
I felt a spray of water.
你們用飲用水過潑水節呢？
You are playing holi with drinking water?
是的，姨媽 -不，阿姨我們隻是……
You are right, aunt. - No, aunty. We were simply.
罰款300
300 rupees will be increased.
阿姨，阿姨-邦蒂！
Aunty. Aunty. - Bunty!
阿姨你聽我說，阿姨！
Aunty, listen to me. Aunty!
我就像你兒子邦迪……
I am just like your Bunty.
媽！
Mummy!
我以後去旁邊的研究所取水
I will fill water from the neighboring institute.
我才不會付錢給這個老巫婆! 該死的
But will not pay this witch! Bloody grouch.
拿著，我已經簽了名
Take this. I've signed it.
你想怎麼寫就怎麼寫吧，混蛋！
Fill what you want in it. Son of a witch!
對不起 -冇關係，兄弟
Sorry, pal. - It's okay, bro.
“隻有雲才能理解大地的渴望”
'Only a cloud understands the thirst of the Earth.'
嘿，庫馬爾維什瓦斯! 來-去哪裏？
Hey, Kumar Vishwas! Come. - Where?
來吧
Come along.
我們已經給了零分
We have given it..
但是隻有當每個人都他打零分時，巴特拉才會被解職
..but Batla will only be removed when everyone gives bad feedback.
“冇有朋友的生活有什麼意義? ”
"What good is a life with no friends?"
拿著，兄弟，我填好了
Take this, bro. I filled the form.
趕走那個惡棍肖漢！
Remove that scoundrel Chauhan!
教員的名字是巴特拉
The faculty's name is Batla.
肖漢先生是A2的老師，不是 A5
Chauhan sir teaches in A2, not in A5.
哦，糟糕! 我掉到 A5了？
Oh crap! I've fallen till A5?
“不是根據地圖，不是根據宗教或需求”
"Not by maps, not by religion or by need."
“我的世界是由朋友組成的”
"My world is made up of friends."
“由你的愛，你的聲音和你的崇拜組成”
"Made up of your love, your sound and your worship."
“我的世界是由朋友組成的”
"My world is made up of friends."
等一下
Just a minute.
不，我不會給出負麵的反饋，也不會讓你給出負麵的反饋
No. Neither will I give a negative feedback and nor will let you give it.
為什麼? 他是你叔叔嗎?-是的！
Why? Is he your uncle? - Yes!
他是你叔叔?-是的
He is your uncle? - Yes.
家人?-是的，家人
Family? - Yes. Family.
兄弟，教學風格……巴特拉? -零分
Look, bro. Teaching style.. Batla? - Zero.
兩分吧，給這個可憐的家夥打個兩分
Two. Two. Let's give the poor chap two.
解答能力 -零！
Doubt solving. - Zero!
一分，一分
One. One. One.
個性 -零！
Personality. - Zero!
零，零，零
Zero. Zero. Zero.
還有守時-零
And punctuality. - Nil.
對不起，我每天午飯前和晚飯後都要背誦一次元素周期錶
Sorry. I revise my periodic table once daily before lunch and after dinner.
很好
That's nice.
非常好！
Very nice!
錶格?-哦，反饋錶格！
The form? - Oh, feedback form!
我在無機化學課上學得很好，所以不需要填錶了
I am doing well in Inorganic so, no need for me to fill it up.
再見，我還要複習所有的原子半徑
Well, bye. I have to revise all the atomic radii too.
我們走，瓦巴夫，來吧
Let's go, Vaibhav. Come.
我們在 A5，但我們不是命中註定
We are in A5 but we are not destined..
能像 A6的學生一樣解決獎勵題
..to be able to solve the chocolate problem like the A6 students.
你說什麼？
What did you say?
非常好的主動性！
Very nice initiative!
巴特拉應該換了
Batla should be changed.
事實上，這個培訓班的每一位老師都應該換掉
In fact, every teacher in this coaching class should be changed.
不，不，這個行業應該改變
No, no. This coaching industry should change.
考試模式、教學大綱、課程設置
Exam pattern, syllabus, curriculum. Pedagogy should change.
理工學院應該改，整個教育體係都應該改
IIT should change. This whole educational system should change.
為此……
And for that..
應該改變父權製
..patriarchy should change.
你覺得怎麼樣，施萬吉？
What do you think, Shivangi?
我認為你應該先上課
I think you should attend class first.
A1，A2，A3，A4，A5.
A1, A2, A3, A4, A5. Inorganic.
無機物下的 AWS 是什麼？
What is AWS under inorganic?
阿瓦斯，以後他教我們嗎?-什麼? 巴特拉走了？
Awasthi. Will he teach us now? - What? Batla is gone?
他走得很體麵
He acted very respectable.
他不是離開的，而是被離開的
He isn't gone. He has been removed.
叔叔
Uncle.
巴特拉先生-你好
Mr. Batla. - Hi.
你好 -好，坐，坐，坐
How are you? - Yes. Sit. Sit. Sit.
什麼風把你吹來了？
So, tell me. What brings you here?
我隻是想和你談談，先生
I just wanted to talk to you, sir.
嗯，你說吧-先生，我不能繼續在A5授課了
Yes, yes. Tell me. - Sir, I've lost A5.
是的-如果您能讓我上額外的課來解決疑問的話……
Yes. - If you could let me give extra classes to resolve doubts..
對無機化學課程也有疑問嗎? 誰會來上課，先生？
Doubt classes that too of Inorganic? Who will attend, sir?
隻要不降低我的工資，我什麼都願意做
Just don't decrease my salary. I will do anything.
給我一個低年級的班
Give me a junior class if you wish.
我還可以教八年級的物理
I can even teach 8th grade physics.
你怎麼能這麼說? 我們都很尊敬你
How can you say that, sir? You are respectable to us, sir.
不是這樣的，先生，當無機化學需要刻苦學習時
Not true, sir. The other subjects are respected..
其他學科才會收到尊重-是的
..when inorganic demands the most hard work. - Yes.
每天早上都要複習
One has to revise every morning.
然而其他人的工資更高
Yet the others have better salaries.
聽著，先生，數學和物理老師都是理工學院畢業的
Look, sir. Math and Physics are taught by IITians.
如果給他們錢少了一定會跳槽的
Pay less to them and other institutes poach them.
這就是姐夫付給他們高薪的原因
That's why brother-in-law pays them so much.
我又能怎麼樣呢，先生？
What can I do in this matter, sir?
我隻能給你侄子提供獎學金，對不對？
I could only offer your nephew a scholarship. Did I or didn't I?
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
事實上，他並冇有得獎學金的資格
When in fact, he didn't deserve it.
但就算是要換掉我，饒先生也是個不錯的替代者
But, sir, even if I was to be removed Mr. Rao. would've been a respectable replacement.
或者是 A6的老師帕敏德
Or maybe that teacher of A6. Parminder.
即使是他也會是一個更好的選擇
Even he would have been a better option.
但是，你卻用我的下屬代替了我
But sir, you replaced me with my junior.
他就是個神經病
You know what, sir? He is a psycho.
他什麼都不懂，還經常來聽我的課
He doesn't know anything. He used to attend my lectures.
那樣的話，你自己也有問題，不是嗎？
In that case, sir, even you made a mistake, didn't you?
初級和高級在無機化學裏無關緊要
Junior and senior don't matter in inorganic, sir.
總得有人留下，所以我們就留下了他
Someone had to be retained. So, we did.
那個可憐的家夥肯定是個神經病
And that poor chap will be a psycho.
在過去的四個月裏，他也一直在家裏無所事事
He too has been idling at home for the past 4 months.
他還能再空閒四個月，他有兩家旅館
He can idle another four months. He owns two hostels.
告訴我，先生，如果他是一個真正的老師
Tell me something, sir. If he was a true teacher..
他現在不是應該加入什麼教師學院了嗎？
..wouldn't he join some coaching institute by now?
你為什麼要取笑這個可憐的家夥，先生？
Why are you making fun of the poor chap, sir?
就連你都知道，冇有一所學院會挖角化學老師
Even you are aware no institute poaches Inorganic faculty.
站起來! 快點站起來！
Up! Stand up quickly!
如果你不知道這個例外情況，那麼到今天為止你都學了什麼？
What have you studied till date if you don't know this exception?
今天打電話給你的父母，告訴他們你考不上印度理工
Call your family today and tell them you won't be able to crack IIT.
如果你冇有勇氣告訴他們，那就下載個抖音
And if you don't have the courage to tell them, then download 'tic tok'.
許多像你這樣的混蛋在那裏麵跳舞，甚至賺得還不少
Many jerks like you dance there and even earn more than they deserve.
我第一個給你點贊
I'll be your first customer. Take this!
15道題才得4分
You scored four out of fifteen.
先生，你們講解過後麵的超綱題嗎?-是的
Sir, do you discuss the chocolate problems? - Yes, yes.
我當然知道-那麼這個題例外的原因是什麼
Of course I do. - So what is the reason for this exception...
但我隻和A1的學生討論
But only with A1 batch students.
因為他們不會像A5學生那樣問愚蠢的問題
..because they don't ask stupid questions like A5 students.
"這些都是事實，但是不行"
These are facts, information. But no!
“我們需要邏輯”
"We want logic."
"先生，為什麼紙幣隻有100和50盧比的麵額？"
Sir, why do notes only come in 100 and 50 rupee denominations?
"為什麼冇有75？"
Why not 75?
"為什麼蘭比爾選擇了阿莉亞? 為什麼不是迪皮卡？"
Why did Ranbir choose Alia? Why not Deepika?
你隻要記住就可以了
Simply memorize what's written and be done with it.
但是不行! “我們要邏輯，我們要成為頂級人物”
But no! "We want logic. We want to be toppers."
“先生，你知道為什麼我是 A5而不是 A1的嗎？
"Sir, do you know why I am a topper from A5 and not from A1?
因為我是蠢驢”
Because I am an ass."
咿哈! 咿哈! 咿哈！
Hee-haw! Hee-haw! Hee-haw!
如果你想學好無機化學，那就照我說的做
If you want to learn inorganic then you do as I tell you.
繼續背，就這樣！
Keep memorizing it. That's that!
毫無疑問
No questions asked.
大家都明白了嗎?-是的，長官！
Everyone got it!? - Yes, sir!
大聲說出來-是，長官！
Say it aloud. - Yes, sir!
我聽不見-是，長官！
I can't hear you. - Yes, sir!
很好！
Good!
現在我們來看一些97年的真題
Now some questions from JEE '97.
我們可以解出來的
We shall solve them.
這題對你們來說真的很重要
They're really important for you guys.
打開你的筆記本
Remove your note books.
先生，我們有個請求
Sir, we have a request.
你付分期付款了嗎?-我們付了，先生！
Have you paid the installment? - We paid it, sir!
我們很久以前就付清了
We paid it long ago.
好吧說吧
Okay, talk.
先生，你..
Sir, you..
先生，化學老師還能換人嗎？
Sir, can the Inorganic faculty be changed once again?
可以
Yes.
為什麼不呢？
Why not?
明年填寫反饋錶
Fill the feedback form next year.
就可以換了
It'll be changed.
先生，明年就太晚了，先生
Sir. Next year will be too late, sir.
你為什麼不讓巴特拉複職呢，先生？
Why don't you reinstate Batla sir?
你們這些冇用的家夥就不配填反饋錶
You worthless chaps should never be given the feedback forms.
頂尖的學生都冇大驚小怪
The toppers never make any fuss.
出去！
Get out!
就這還想考印度理工
They want to be IITians.
米納爾也很沮喪，先生
Meenal is also frustrated, sir.
她怎麼了
What happened to her? - Hee-haw. Hee-haw.
給她打電話
Call Meenal.
你這個白癡! 給我！
You idiot! Give it to me!
我告訴過你很多次了，你要把這個號碼牢記在心
I've told you so many times you should know topper's phone numbers by heart.
你好哦，可愛的孩子米納爾
Hello. Oh sweet child Meenal.
(哭泣)
(sobs)
新來的化學老師有什麼問題嗎？
Is there any... problem with the new sir?
(哭泣)
(sobs)
告訴我，孩子
Tell me, child.
是的，先生，有一點
Yes, sir. A little bit.
那你還等什麼? 你是今年的頭牌
Then why did you wait? You are this year's topper.
頭牌？
Topper?
- 女生頭牌
- Girls topper.
如果有什麼事，你應該立即給我發信息
If anything happens, you should message me immediately.
所以你才有我的私人電話
That's why you have my personal number.
是的，先生我換了手機，所以你的號碼弄丟了
Yes, sir. I changed my phone so, your number got misplaced.
來，記好
Take it down.
9862...
9-8-6-2...
我一會兒給你
I'll give it to you later.
好吧
Okay.
把阿瓦斯換到基礎班
Put Awasthi in the foundation course.
告訴我，你想要哪個先生？
Tell me. Which sir would you like?
來自 A6的老師
The teacher from A6.
是的，A6的老師
Yes. The teacher from A6.
來自 A6的老師
The teacher from A6.
帕... 米... 德
Par...min...der.
好的-好的
Okay - Yes.
好吧
Okay.
聽著，她是這家夥的女朋友
Look. She is this dude's girlfriend..
但是誰在追她? 所有科塔的男孩？
..but who all are chasing her? All the boys in Kota?
哪裏來的男孩?-科塔的男孩！
The boys from where? - Boys in Kota!
但是這家夥的女朋友拒絕了所有人，除了“這家夥”
But dude's girlfriend refuses everyone except 'the dude'.
那這家夥算什麼?-例外
So what does that make the dude? - Exception.
那他的女朋友是什麼？
And what does that make the girlfriend?
無辜的，她愛上那個混蛋了！
Innocent. She fell for that jerk!
我們必須了解這件事的要點
We must understand the gist of the matter.
任何有化學反應的地方都有什麼?-例外！
Anywhere there is chemistry, there is? - Exception!
非常好! 這很有趣
Very good! This is fun.
所以那家夥在課堂外看到我，說無機化學是危險的
So the dude sees me outside the class and says Inorganic chemistry is dangerous.
這非常複雜
It is very complicated.
我不幹了
I will quit.
我說，兄弟，你的女朋友也很複雜
I said, brother, your girlfriend is also complicated.
你會離開她嗎？
Do you leave her?
- 不會，你要怎麼做?-你會時刻關註她
No. What do you do with her? You pay her attention.
你把註意力集中在她身上，好好跟她說話
You focus on her. You talk to her nicely.
肖納，莫娜，巴佈，傑杜，托納
Shona. Mona. Babu. Jadu. Tona.
還會叫什麼？
What else do you call?
看看，這個聽到這個，連坐在後排聽課的教師都很專註
Look at that. On hearing it even the Bajrang dal at the back is attentive.
你好，坐直了
Hello. Sit straight.
是的
Yes.
你覺得這很有趣，兄弟
You find it very amusing, bro.
站起來
Stand up.
你有女朋友嗎？
You have a girlfriend?
你冇有，情理之中
You don't. That's not surprising.
坐下
Sit down.
正如這位小老弟是孤獨的，同樣，硼也是孤獨的
Just as our brother here is alone, similarly boron is alone.
硼缺少電子，但是冇有人給它
Boron is short of electrons but nobody is giving it.
那麼，我們該怎麼辦？
So, what will we do?
它會繼續獨自存在嗎？
Will it remain alone?
- 我們的兄弟一個人坐著嗎?-不
Is our brother sitting alone? No.
哥哥發現一隻和他一模一樣的猴子
Brother found a monkey just like him.
他發現了什麼?-猴子！
What did he find? - Monkey!
朋友，隻有我會說猴子
Friend. Only I will say monkey.
所以硼和自己是一樣的
So the boron finds boron like itself..
並與之形成一種聯係
..and forms a bond with it.
不是詹姆斯 · 邦德，是連接
Not James Bond. Bond.
當兩個朋友結合在一起，這叫什麼？
When two friends make a bond what is it called?
它會變成一根香蕉，先生
It will become a banana, sir.
非常好的回答！
Very good answer!
它會形成一個香蕉鍵
It will form a banana bond.
學者們稱之為三中心到兩個電子鍵
The educated people call it three-center to two electron bond.
它叫什麼?-三個中心對兩個電子鍵！
What is it called? - Three-center to two electron bond!
不需要記住這個，它不會幫助走進印度理工
No need to remember that. It will not help you clear IIT.
我們的目標是什麼?-印度理工
What do we want to clear? - IIT!
非常好！
Very good!
那麼你們兩個，你們有聯係嗎？
So you two. Have you formed a bond?
你們之間有聯係嗎？
Have you formed a bond?
來吧，寫在你的書上
Come on. Write in your book.
當兩個原子結合形成類似的鍵時
When two atoms combine to form a bond of similar type..
由於缺乏電子，這種鍵被稱為香蕉鍵
..due to lack of electrons, the bond is known as banana bond.
孩子們，如果有任何關於香蕉鍵的問題，我們會做嗎？
Children, if there is any question on banana bond, we will do it?
會！
Yes, sir!
也就是說香蕉鍵?-冇問題
That means banana bond? - Is not a problem.
鈴聲已經響了
The bell has rung.
回去記得做作業，明天再交上來
Everyone will complete their sheets and bring them in tomorrow.
那些冇有完成的人會挨我一拳，好嗎？
Those who don't complete it will get a punch from me. Okay?
- 再見-先生! 先生! 先生! 我們來唱首歌吧
Bye. - Sir! Sir! Sir! Let's have a song.
一首歌，先生
A song, sir.
是的，先生，一首歌，先生
Yes, sir. A song, sir.
求你了，先生求你了……
Please, sir. Please, sir. Please, sir. Please, sir.
安靜！
Silence!
你是來聽歌的嗎? 讓我唱歌？
Are you here to listen to songs? I sing songs?
這是《印度偶像》嗎？
Is this 'Indian Idol'?
你們父母花錢送你來是聽歌的嗎？
Is this why your parents pay your fees?
還讓我唱首歌……
Sing a song, sir. Sing a song.
他解釋得很清楚，很簡單
He explains so well. He made it so easy.
不僅是個好老師，也是個不錯的歌手
Apart from being the best teacher he is the best singer also.
A6的同學都是這麼說的
The boys from A6 said so.
但是他們從來冇有說過他還很幽默-冇錯
But they never said he makes you laugh so much too. - That's right.
我發誓，如果他不是老師，一定能上脫口秀大會
I swear if he wasn't a teacher he would surely do stand up comedy.
太好了，我們得到了無機化學的傑圖·拜亞-是的
Praise the lord. Its like we got the 'Jeetu Bhaiya' of Inorganic chemistry. - Yes.
我清楚地記得整堂課
I remember the whole lecture vividly.
我不需要參考我的筆記就能完成DPP
I won't have to refer to my notes to do the DPP.
真不錯，他一邊教我們唱歌，這才是課堂應該有的樣子
It's nice. He teaches us while singing. That's how the class should be.
今天，我的大腦開始産生化學反應
Today my brain has opened to chemistry.
門已經開了 -我今天開悟了
It's already open. - It has opened today.
我說門已經開了
The door is already open.
把這裏的蜘蛛網清理幹淨
Clean all the cobwebs from here.
把箱子挪開，把所有的垃圾都扔掉
Move the suitcases and throw away all the garbage.
少爺回來了
Welcome, prince.
在我看來，我要從你的押金裏麵扣除一些衛生費了
It seems to me I'll have to cut money from your security now.
這又是怎麼了，阿姨?-這是什麼？
What happened now, aunty? - What is this?
地闆
The floor.
地闆上是什麼?-你
What is on the floor? - You.
別跟我耍小聰明
You are being a wise ass.
- 這是什麼汙漬? -脆皮
What kind of stains are those? Crispy. Crispy.
即使是蜥蜴也不能去除這些汙漬
Even lizol can't remove these.
我警告過你，我不想在我的科塔大理石上留下任何痕跡
I am warning you. I am warning you I don't want even a scratch on my Kota marble.
這不是科塔的大理石，這是科塔的石頭
This is not Kota marble. It is Kota stone.
你再說一遍？
What did you say to my face?
阿姨，以後我們對你的大理石要比對我們的書更加小心
Aunty, hereafter we shall take more care of your marble than our books.
哦，不
Oh, no.
以後我們每天都要打掃這裏
Hereafter we will have daily cleaning here..
你每個月要付500盧比
..and you will have to pay 500 rupees per month for it.
我們走
Let's go.
嘿!-讓開，你甚至都冇洗澡
Hey! - Get out of my way. You don't even shower.
阿姨，您這也冇熱水啊
'Aunty, give me hot water.'
骯髒的流氓
Filthy rascals.
我希望我能有這個阿姨的反饋錶
I wish I had a feedback form for this Tarka as well.
別管這個了，你現在是個英雄
Never mind Supankha. You are a hero.
如果不是因為你，化學老師也不能換
If it hadn't been for you neither would the inorganic teacher change..
我的運氣也不會
..nor would my luck.
兄弟，我會把我的前兩個超綱起獎勵作為供品給你
Brother, I will give you my first two chocolates as offerings.
別客氣，老弟
Its alright, junior.
來吧，孩子們，把你們的試卷打開，我們現在開始
Come on, children. Remove your sheets. We shall begin now.
對答案
I will tell you the answers. Check your answers.
第一題，非常簡單的問題，說都不想說了
The first. Very easy question. It's a shame to even discuss it.
答案是A，記好了，然後繼續下一題
The answer is A. Mark it and move on. Tally it.
第二題選B
Tell me the second. B. ZnS.
你們誰做過第三題？ 這是一個非常簡單的問題
Which of you have done the third? It is a very easy question.
這題口算就能解決，你要是用筆算那就太不應該了
We shall solve it orally. Its a shame if you use your pens.
答案是B
The answer is B.
這是什麼? 這麼簡單的問題簡直浪費時間
What is this? Such easy questions. Time waste.
非常基礎的問題，答案是C
Even more basic question. C is the answer.
如果你做錯了，好好檢查一下自己吧
If you got this wrong, get yourself checked.
第四題
Question number 4.
答案是B，非常基礎
The answer is B. Very basic.
答案是C 我上節課講過
The answer is C. I did it in the last class.
你們應該冇問題
You should have no problem.
第六個問題，讓我們回到第八個問題-先生！
Sixth question. Let's go to the eighth question. - Sir!
先生，第七題的答案怎麼可能是A?-孩子，那個……
Sir. How can the answer to question 7 be A? - Son, that..
它應該是C，不是嗎? -我們先對答案，等下我再講解
It should be C, shouldn't it? - Let's complete this and then I will..
不，不，先生，先告訴我
No, no, sir. Tell me this first.
先生，鋁是硼家族的
Sir, aluminum is from the boron family.
它也冇有電子
It doesn't have electrons either.
因此，它會和另一個類似它自己的物質形成一種聯係
So, it will form a bond with another one like itself.
所以它會形成一個香蕉鍵
So it will make a banana bond.
這個並列的契約是什麼？
What is this coordinate covenant bond?
這是個例外，孩子，我在課堂上教過你
That is the exception, son. I taught you that in class.
但是，先生，香蕉鍵本身就是一個例外
But, sir, the banana bond is an exception in itself.
孩子，這是個例外
Son, this is an exception to the exception.
同學們，我說過化學的第一法則是什麼？
Class, what did I say was the first rule of chemistry?
任何有化學反應的地方都有什麼?-例外！
Anywhere there is chemistry, there is? - Exception!
我們繼續
Let's move on.
第八題
The eighth question. D.
別緊張，我們會解決超綱題的
Don't take stress. We will solve the chocolate problem.
嘿，兄弟! 怎麼了?-滾開！
Hey, bro! What's up? - Scram!
滾！ 滾！-快走
Scram! Scram! - Go.
他瘋了嗎？
Is he crazy?
米納，別再幻想了
Meena, get out of this illusion.
我們不會解開獎勵題的
We are not going to get chocolate.
你明白嗎? 我們什麼也做不了
Do you understand? We won't be able to do anything.
不管換多少老師，我們也做不了什麼
We won't be able to do anything no matter how many teachers are changed.
我打聽了一下
I made enquiries.
這批 A6級的學生也參加了我們學院的相關課程
The A6 batch students have also taken a corresponddence course of our institute.
在做dpp之前，他們就已經學過了
The scoundrels have the solutions before the DPP is discussed.
他們有巧克力，但是他們在考試中冇有得分
They get chocolate but they don't score marks in the test.
這就是他們仍然在A6的原因
That's why they are still in A6.
我們為什麼不去找個化學私教呢
Why don't we take private classes outside the institute for inorganic.
- 真的?-是的
Really? - Yes.
那又能怎樣呢？
And what will we gain from it?
找私教又能怎樣？
What will we gain from it? What will we gain?
能幫我們提高成績，不是嗎?
They will teach us well, won't they? Even these people are teaching us well.
米納，問題不在於老師
Meena, the problem is not with the teachers.
問題在於這個討厭的學科！
The problem is with this nasty subject!
這是一個無聊透頂的學科！
It is an utterly boring subject!
冇有任何邏輯可言
There are only facts that have no logic.
在邏輯的名義下，例外比規則多得多
There are more exceptions than the number of rules in the name of logic.
在第一個八隅律中，他們說應該隻有8個電子
In the first octet rule they say there should be only 8 electrons..
但是任何數量的電子都會産生化合物
..but then any number of electrons are making compounds.
四，六，七，八，十
Four. Six. Seven. Eight. Ten.
- 十二個-是的
And Twelve. - Yes.
一個原子有這麼多模型
One atom has so many models.
首先他們教你道爾頓的模型
First they teach you Dalton's model.
當你明白的時候，他們會說，“哦，這是不正確的”
The moment you understand it they say, "Oh, this is incorrect."
好吧，假設他們犯了一次錯誤
Alright. Let's say they made a mistake once.
然後他們教你湯普森梅子佈丁模型，即使這是錯誤的
Then they teach you Thompson plum pudding model. Even that is wrong.
然後他們教你盧瑟福模型，然而這也是不正確的
Then they teach you Rutherford model. Even that is incorrect.
那你為什麼要教我們？
Then why are you teaching us?
坐下來，別急
Make it first. Sit down and make it.
我們會教你的
No, no, no. We will teach you.
我們會教你波爾的模型
We will teach you. Bohr's model.
海森堡模型
Heisenberg model.
冇有一個是完全正確的
None of them are entirely correct.
他們說這是例外，完全是在愚弄我們
These people are making fools of us by calling it exception.
這不是例外，而是借口，純粹的借口
This is not an exception. It is an excuse. Pure excuse.
他們並冇有給出解題的理論依據
They don't have a theory that gives you all the answers.
他們怎麼會有理論? 告訴我，他們怎麼會有理論？
And how could they have a theory? Tell me. How could they have it?
像愛因斯坦和牛頓這樣的天才提出了理論
Geniuses like Einstein and Newton gave theories.
他們從不學這種低能的學科
They never read this moronic subject.
這冇有邏輯
There's no logic.
他們隻有例外，和更多的例外
All they have is exception, exception and exception.
《盜夢空間》並冇有像這些意外那樣讓我感到睏惑
'Inception' did not confuse me as much as exception has.
在這裏，每個原子都可以隨心所欲地行動和反應
Every atom acts and reacts as it pleases here.
它們的氧化狀態都發生了變化
The oxidation state of all of them changes.
加二減七加三減一半
Plus two. Minus seven. Plus three. Minus half.
即使氧的氧化狀態也是不固定的
Even the oxidation state of oxygen is not fixed.
當你自己的元素不在乎的時候
When your own elements don't give a damn..
那為什麼要組建一個幸福的周期性家庭? 為什麼？
..then why make a happy periodic family? Why?
學學人家數學
Learn from math. Learn.
零到九是固定的
Zero to nine is fixed once and for all. Final.
但在化學，元素直到現在都是不固定的。
But here, their elements aren't fixed till date.
每年都有新的元素出現
Something new crops up every year.
砰! 113號是今年抽獎的號碼
Boom! Number 113 is the number picked in this year's lucky draw.
我們就把它叫做'鍬'好了
We shall call it! Nikenugium. No, no, no. Nikeniugium!
該死! 背誦梵文咒語都比這容易
Damn it! It is easier to recite a Sanskrit mantra.
牛頓給了我們三個定律，三個
Newton gave us three laws. Three.
我們物理學的一半都被它覆蓋了
Half our physics is covered with it..
但在這裏，每個問題都有一個新規則
..but here, there is a new rule for every question.
承認吧，承認你不像物理和數學那樣有邏輯
Admit it. Admit that you are not logical like physics and math.
好吧，吃點...-不！
Okay. Eat some.. - No!
告訴我，這很簡單
Tell me something. It is simple.
如果你把蘋果拋嚮空中會發生什麼？
What will happen if you toss an apple in the air?
它會掉下來-它會掉下來? 對吧？
It will fall. - It will fall? It will fall?
物理學上它會掉下來，但是化學上並不會
But it will fall in physics. It won't fall in chemistry.
化學中會發生什麼? 會有空間位阻
What will happen in chemistry? There will be steric hindrance.
如果這還不夠，那麼共鳴，誘導效應
If that's not enough then resonance, inductive effect.
一切都會發生，任何事都可能發生
Everything will happen. Anything can happen here.
他們甚至不會簡單地命名顔色
They don't even name the colors simply.
綠色不叫綠色，叫蘋果綠，紅色不叫紅色，叫深紅色
It's not green. It's apple green. It's not red. It's crimson red.
粉紅不叫粉紅，叫桃紅！
It's not pink. It's hot pink!
這就是為什麼隻有女孩子才會這麼擅長化學
That's why only girls are so good at chemistry.
還會讓你做無厘頭的事情
They make you do nonsense.
火焰試驗. 鹽分析. 滴定. 佈朗環試驗
Flame test. Salt analysis. Titration. Brown ring test.
還有臭雞蛋的味道，為什麼我要聞到臭雞蛋的味道？
Rotten eggs smell. Why should I smell a rotten egg?
為什麼? 我是個婆羅門（吃素）！
Why? I am a Brahmin!
原子大小趨勢電離勢趨勢
Atomic size trend. Ionization potential trend.
電子親和力趨勢，電子負性趨勢，水平趨勢
Electron-affinity trend. Electron -negativity trend. Horizontal trend.
縱嚮趨勢
Vertical trend.
當你可以預測某事時，你可以把它稱為一種趨勢
You can call something a trend when you can predict something with it.
如果任何時間任何地點發生任何事情，就像“印度斯坦的暴徒”一樣
If anything is happening anywhere and anytime like 'Thugs of Hindustan'..
那他們怎麼能稱之為趨勢呢？
..then how can they call it a trend?
他們怎麼能這麼說？
How can they call it that?
我告訴你，米納
I am telling you, Meena.
化學不是一門學科，它是主觀的
Chemistry is not a subject. It is subjective.
我為這個學科付出了很多
I did so much for this subject.
作業，筆記，卡片，我坐在前排
Assignments, notes, flash cards. I sat in the front row.
換了三個老師，換了學習策略
Changed three teachers. Changed the studying strategy.
但最終的結果是什麼呢? 一無所獲！
But what is the end result? Zilch!
他停不下來了，拜亞哥
He wouldn't stop, Jeetu Bhaiya.
所以我才帶他來見你
That's why I brought him to you.
你的理解是正確的
You have understood it correctly.
問題不在於老師，而在於學科
The problem is not with the teacher, it's with the subject.
你隻能在大學裏找到物理學家一定是有原因的
There must be some reason you find physicists only in universities..
而你在每個角落都能找到藥劑師
..while you find chemists at every corner.
你知道你不能背那麼多東西，對吧？
You understand that you cannot memorize so much, right?
好吧-但是這個問題要怎麼解決呢，拜亞哥
Fine. - But how does that solve the problem, Bhaiya?
你不知道嗎？-不知道
It isn't? - No.
我認為這很簡單
I thought it was simple.
好吧，假設你要去約會
Okay, let's say you have to go on a date.
你有女朋友嗎?-冇有
You have a girlfriend? - No.
假設你有一個像卡特裏娜這樣的性感女友
Let's assume you have a hot girl like Katrina.
她很準時，八點整打電話給你
Ma'am is punctual. She calls you at 8 o'clock sharp.
如果你要去約會，你會帶一份禮物給她，是嗎？
If you're going on a date you will take a gift for her, won't you?
香檳，花束 -還有粉紅的泰迪玩偶
Champagne, bouquet.. - Teddy bear. Pink.
你的想法非常不同
Your ideas are very different.
無論如何，讓我們假設你拿了一個玩偶
Anyway, let's assume you take a teddy bear.
你在路上碰到一個小偷
You bump into a thief on the way.
他抓起玩偶就跑了
He snatches the teddy bear and runs.
你會怎麼做?-他怎麼能逃跑呢？
What will you do? - How can he run away?
我要抓住他，揍他一頓
I will catch hold of him and punch him.
當然，理想情況下你應該這麼做
Of course. Ideally that's what you should do.
但是小偷很快
But the thief is fast.
現在你手裏還有兩份禮物，然後呢？
And you have two gifts in your hands. Then?
然後我們大聲尖叫，肯定會有人來幫忙的
Then we scream aloud. Someone will surely help.
這可能是一種方法
That could be one approach.
也許會成功，你會怎麼做？
Maybe it will work. What will you do?
我會忘記這個玩偶
I will forget about the gift..
然後帶著剩下的兩個禮物沖過去
..and rush with the remaining two gifts.
所以，趕快！
So, rush!
我告訴過你這很簡單，印度理工是個性感的女孩
I told you it is simple. IIT is the hot gal.
當然花束和香檳是數學和物理
Sure. The bouquet and champagne are math and physics..
. . 而泰迪熊就是
..while the teddy is inorganic chemistry..
我們學不會的化學
..which we are unable to get hold of.
但是，拜亞哥，現實生活中的女朋友就是想要泰迪熊
But, Bhaiya, the real life girlfriend wants the teddy.
不學化學我就考不上印度理工學院
I won't get admission into IIT without inorganic.
誰說的？
Who says so?
你們還有誰是印度理工畢業的嗎？
Who is the IITian in this room?
你以為我會像傻瓜一樣背化學嗎？
Do you think I memorized chemistry like a jackass?
在你準備考試之前，先學習考試
Before you study for an exam, study the exam.
你覺得怎麼樣？在這六個小時裏，你需要得多少分才能考上印度理工？
What do you think? How much do you need to score during those six hours to get into top five IITs?
90%-不，不，你瘋了嗎? 肯定要95%才行
90 percent for top five.. - No, no. Are you insane? 95 percent.
95 percent.
你們要如何麵對這個野蠻的世界?
How will you face this savage world?
它會把你生吞活剝了，40%
It will eat you alive! 40 percent.
隻需要40%？
Only 40 percent for top five?
得到40%就能排前五了？
Only 40 percent for top five IIT?
你在開玩笑嗎，拜亞哥？
You are kidding, aren't you, Bhaiyar?
互聯網上有很多東西
There are many things apart from memes on the internet.
去看看非學術的講座視頻： IIT JEE 的戰略
Go and watch videos of Unacademy. Strategy for IIT JEE.
JEE的出題者和科學家會抽出時間為你製作一些視頻
JEE toppers and scientists take time out to make some videos for you.
你拜亞哥我能解決所有問題嗎？
At least do that much. Is your Jeetu Bhaiya going to solve everything?
即使省略教學大綱的60%
Even if omit 60 percent of the syllabus..
你還是有機會進入印度理工學院
..you still stand a chance to get into IIT.
無機化學的教學大綱可能非常龐大
The syllabus for inorganic chemistry might be vast.
所以，隨它去吧
So, let it be.
它在我們的考試中有多重？
How much weightage does it carry in our exam?
化學在我們的考試中會佔多大比重? 告訴我
How much weightage would chemistry carry in our exam? Tell me.
化學是三分之一-33%
Chemistry would be one-third. - 33 percent.
其中三分之一是. .-11%
One third of that would be.. - 11 percent.
想想吧
Think about it.
你想追求這11% 的分數嗎
Do you want to chase 11 percent..
... 弄皺你剛熨好的褲子
..and ruin the crease on your trousers..
還是專註於89% ？
..or focus on 89 percent?
得分40% ，然後享受在印度理工的四年
Score 40 percent and then enjoy in a good IIT for four years.
拜亞哥，我今天要把所有的無機化學書都燒掉
Bhaiya, I shall burn up all the sheets of Inorganic today.
-就這樣!-那樣不對
End of story! - That's wrong.
是的，這是知識，燒書是罪惡的
Yes. It is knowledge. It is a sin.
把它當廢紙賣掉
Sell it as waste paper.
還能換一些錢用它吃零食
You will get some money. Eat some snacks with it.
但是，拜亞哥，化學可以提高名次不是嗎？
But, Jeetu Bhaiya, one can improve one's rank with inorganic, right?
化學提高了那些正在獲得排名的人的排名
Inorganic improves the rank of those who are actually getting a rank.
但在你的情況下，它會讓你失去排名
But in your case, it will leave you rankless.
所以，解決這些問題的最好方法
So, the best way to tackle problems like these..
就是不要摻和進來
..is not to get involved. Just take the fast lane.
你明白嗎? 快點，你們這些家夥，走吧
Do you understand? Come on, you guys. Leave. Leave.
去吧
Go.
你為什麼看起來這麼睏惑，米納？
Why do you look so confused, Meena?
但是，拜亞哥，那天你說..
But, Jeetu Bhaiya, the other day you said..
如果你在生活中遇到睏難，要勇敢麵對
..if you have a problem in life you confront it.
讓你的問題成為挑戰，讓挑戰成為習慣，勇往直前
Make your problem a dare. Make your dare a habit and forge ahead.
今天你卻說讓我們放棄化學
Today you are saying to let Inorganic go if we don't know it.
孩子，無機化學是個例外
Son, Inorganic chemistry is an exception.
走吧，走吧
Come on. Leave.
謝謝你，拜亞哥
Thank you, Bhaiya.
考試的目標不應該是解決所有的問題
Objective in the exams should not be to solve all the problems..
而是為了解決最多的問題
..but to solve the maximum number of questions.
如果問題是非常睏惑和費時的，他們可以跳過它
If the problem is very confusing and time consuming, they you can skip it.
如果你還有剩餘的時間，再回頭去看
If you have any time remaining then get back to it.
記住，並不是每個問題都是要解決的
Bear in mind, not every problem is meant to be solved.
瓦伊巴夫潘迪!-阿姨？
Vaibhav Pandey! - Aunty?
我告訴過你多少次了，不要扔那麼多衣服
I've told you so many times not to put so many clothes..
在二手洗衣機裏
..in the second hand washing machine.
你考慮過水和電嗎？
Do you think about electricity and water?
阿姨
Aunty.
近來可好？
How are you?
拿著這個，這是你的額外費用
Take this. This is your extra charge.
我每個月都會給你
And I shall give it to you every month.
麻煩您整個月都不要打擾我
Just don't disturb me for the entire month.
謝謝你
Thank you.